blogherald.com 2006-06-15

# BlogMedia, Inc. :: Weblog Content Network & Services

### BlogMedia, Inc. Privacy Policy

This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for BlogMedia, Inc. and its network of websites and services. 

This statement is our notification of: 

  * What personally identifiable information of yours or third party personal information is collected from you through this web site
  * The organization collecting the information.
  * How the information is used.
  * With whom the information may be shared.
  * What choices are available to you regarding collection, use, and distribution of the information.
  * The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of information under our control.
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

#### Information Collection and Use

BlogMedia, Inc. is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. BlogMedia, Inc. collects information from our users at several different points on our web sites. 

#### Registration

In order to use portions of some of our websites, a user must first complete the registration form. During registration a user is required to give their contact information (such as their name, address, email address, and other factors). This information is used to contact the user about the services on our site for which they have expressed interest. It is optional for the user to provide demographic information (such as income level and gender), and unique identifiers, but encouraged to do so so we can provide a more personalized experience on our site. 

#### Order - Credit Card Processing

We request information from the user on our order forms. Here, a user must provide contact information and financial information (such as Credit Card Number, Expiration Date, and so on). This information is used for billing purposes. If we have trouble processing an order, this contact information is used to get in touch with the user.

#### Cookies

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. Once the user closes their browser, the cookie simply terminates. For instance, by setting a cookie on our site, the user would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our site. The only drawback to this is that the user will be limited in some areas of our site. For example, the user will not be able to participate in any of our Sweepstakes, Contests or monthly Drawings that take place. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. 

Some of our business partners use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or controlover these cookies, or the information they carry.

#### Log Files

We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

#### Sharing

We will share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person.

We use a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.

We partner with another party to provide specific services. When the user signs up for these services, we will share names, or other contact information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services. 

These parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services.

#### Links

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that BlogMedia, Inc. is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this web site. 

#### Surveys, Contests, Tell-a-Friend, and Co-Registration

From time-to-time our site requests information from users via surveys or contests as well as through Tell-a-Friend and Co-Registration forms. Participation in these activities is completely voluntary and the user therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code, age level). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site. Tell-a-Friend and Co-Registration form usage information will be used to provide information to third-parties 

#### Referrals

If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask them for the friend's name and email address. We will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site. We store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. That information is then deleted. 

#### Security

This web site takes every precaution to protect our users information. When users submit sensitive information via the web site, your information is protected both online and off-line. 

When our registration/order form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry - SSL. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the security icon on your web browser becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, when you are visiting non-secure sites. 

While we use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Our employees must use password-protected screen-savers when they leave their desk. When they return, they must re-enter their password to re-gain access to your information. 

Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Every quarter, as well as any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our customers information is protected. Finally, the servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure environment, behind a locked cage. 

If you have any questions about the security at our web site, you can send an email to support [a t] blogmedia.biz. 

#### Special Offers

We send all new members a welcoming email to verify password and username. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see our choice and opt-out below. 

#### Site & Service Updates

We also send site and service announcement updates to our registered users. Members are not able to un-subscribe from service announcements, which contain important information about the service. We communicate with the users to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account via email or phone. 

#### Correction/Updating Personal Information

If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as your zip code), or if a user no longer desires our service, we will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update or remove that user's personal data provided to us. This can usually be done at the member information page or by emailing Customer Support at support [a t] blogmedia.biz. 

#### Choice/Opt-Out

Our users are given the opportunity to opt-out of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for the information. For example, our registration form has an opt-out mechanism so users who register with our site, but don't want any marketing material, can keep their email address off of our lists. 

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter or promotional materials from our partners may opt-out of receiving these communications by replying to unsubscribe in the subject line in the email or email us at support [a t] blogmedia.biz. 

Users of our site are always notified when their information is being collected by any outside parties. We do this so our users can make an informed choice as to whether or not they should proceed with services that require an outside party. 

#### Notification of Changes

If we change this privacy policy, we will post those changes on our home page so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

#### Questions

Please contact us at privacy [a t] blogmedia.biz if you have any questions about our privacy policy.
